Joshua Nathaniel Dalangin

E-mail: josh 25 4@live.co.uk **Mobile:** +447483262098

Mobile: +447483262098

GitHub: github.com/WS325427 **Portfolio**: www.joshuadalangin.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/joshuadalangin/

Personal Statement

A recent tech degree apprentice graduate with a strong engineering foundation, passion for data visualisation, and eagerness to delve further into the field of analytics. Able to provide proficient time-management, problem-solving skills and attention to detail developed from 4 years of professional consultancy support on top of full stack web-app development, as well as a prior 3 years of physics labs in education. Excited to seek a technical position that can allow the next steps of personal and professional growth whilst contributing effectively towards a company's objectives.

Work Experience

Buro Happold - Data Analyst and Simulation Engineer

Sept 2019 - Present

- Updated and developed features for a legacy, client facing Polymer2 (JavaScript, HTML, CSS) web application, allowing it to branch off from the team as an independent company called SmartViz.
- Designed and developed a new, more optimised, secure, single page, crowd visualisation web application using Django, PostgreSQL and Angular, hosted on Microsoft Azure with GitHub CI/CD features and backend development within a Docker container, returning a high potential in-house service.
- Built the frontend for a **digital twin** of a high school incorporating sensor data with variable parametric scenario modelling using **React** and **Bentley's iTwin Platform**, leading to a successful, live, in-person demo.
- Streamlined the simulation "data outputs to dashboard" workflow using **Python**, increasing efficiency, and allowing a completed simulation model to be visualised on the web, potentially as soon as within the hour.
- Reduced interaction bugs for the in-house simulation client based on C# and WPF during platform upgrades.
- Created 3D visual models of spaces, using Rhino3D, for more captivating presentations and dashboards.
- Devised **Grasshopper** custom scripts to allow for more complicated simulation scenarios, enabling increased confidence in completing projects outside the normal.
- Supported pedestrian flow consultancy with visualisation outputs, analytics, and reports across 25+ projects. Many of which have returned for continued work. Usage of **Microsoft Office: Word, Excel, Powerpoint.**

KFC – Team Member Sept 2014 – Jan 2018

Awarded Staff of the Month twice and Recognition for Respect.

Additional Technical Projects

- Built a temperature sensor system using Raspberry Pi, Node-Red, and electronic components.
- Visualised historical Olympic dataset with dynamic graphs, based on filters, on the web using XAAMP stack.
- Console app for expense and employee logging system using C++
- Created a **Linux** mini home server using an Intel NUC for entertainment such as game hosting and movies.

Education

University of the West of England Sept 2019 - June 2023 1.1 Honours BSc Degree in Digital and Technology Solutions Online Database Management 84% Data Analysis 77% **Project Management** 75% Final Year Synoptic Project 77 % Object Oriented Design 72% **Cloud Computing Platforms** 70% Sept 2015 - June 2019 **Queen's University Belfast** 2.2 Honours BSc Degree in Physics Mathematics for Physics 1 Mathematics for Physics 2 Final Lab Project 76% 89% 76% 84% Computational Method 82% Computational Modelling

Regent House Grammar School

Sept 2008 - June 2015

A-Levels: Maths A* Further Maths A Physics B Chemistry C

GCSEs: Maths A* Additional Maths A* English B

Interests outside of Tech

I like exploring new things and always try to focus on self-improvement. I have earned a green belt in Tai-Jutsu during University, participated in peer mentoring schemes, learnt basics of piano and guitar, and enjoy playing games.